A Guide to the John Z. Bowers papers FA1415
Rockefeller Archive Center
- China, 2.84 Cubic Feet
  - Manchuria - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 11, Folder 278)
    Reprint (in Japanese); Reprint (in Chinese); Notecards, "An Experimental Study of the Venom of the Manchurian Scorpion" by Seiko Kubota; "'The Basic Conception of China' as Viewed by the Japanese Army" by Major-General Hayao Tada; Reprint (in Japanese); Photographs
  - Manchuria - Journal of Oriental Medicine of Manchurian Medical Association (Box 11, Folder 279)
  - Manchuria - Reprint (Box 11, Folder 280)
  - Manchuria - Namman-Igaku-do (Box 11, Folder 281)
  - Manchuria - Hoijin-Alumni Magazine, Given by Mr. Sano, List of Alumni Members (Box 11, Folder 282)
  - Manchuria - First East Mongolian Survey, 1923, Nam-Man (Box 11, Folder 283)
  - Manchuria - NamMan Igaku-do History of 10 Years (Box 11, Folder 284)
  - Manchuria - Data of Economic Research Institute of North China, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 285)
  - Manchuria - Contributions to Medical Work in China by Rockefeller and Missionaries (Box 11, Folder 286)
    Envelope, Pictures of Naman Igakudo; "Contributions to Medical Work in China by Rockefeller and the Missionaries"
  - Manchuria - Yas Kuno (Box 11, Folder 287)
    Notes, Photocopies
  - Manchuria - Light of Manchuria (Box 11, Folder 288)
    "The Light of Manchuria: Public Hygiene in Manchuria and Mongolia"; Correspondence
  - Manchuria - Lamas (Box 12, Folder 289)
    "Mongolia Still Has a Few lamas, But Mostly as a Negative Example"; Notecard
  - Manchuria - Japanese Medicine in Manchuria (Box 12, Folder 290)
    Envelope, Interview with Sano-Irbanan at Keio Kyoto Research on S.M.R.; Notes
  - Manchuria - Unfoldered Materials (Box 12, Folder 291)
    "Folia Pharmacorum Sinicorum, List of Collection of Chinese Materia Medica"; Keio University Medical Library and Information Center
  - Manchuria - Gotō Shimpei (Box 12, Folder 292)
  - Manchuria - Jiji-son: Shina Kyoikudan, Naito Torajiro (Box 12, Folder 293)
    Japanese Visit to China during Cultural Revolution and Refs to Excellence of Naman Igakudo
  - Manchuria - Hospitals in Manchuria and Current History Materials (Box 12, Folder 294)
    Notes; Photocopies
  - Manchuria - Tanaka re: Manchuria (Box 12, Folder 295)
    "Memorial of Premier Tanaka to the Japanese Emperor"
  - South Manchuria Medical College - Missionaries, Oral History - China Missionary Oral History Collection Microfilm Description (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - South Manchuria Medical College - South Manchuria Railway (Medical School) (Box 12, Folder 297)
  - Missionary Schools - Aurora-Chantilly (Box 12, Folder 298)
    Notes; Envelope, Aurora University, "Les Fontaines" Notes; Postcards; "By-laws of the St. Luke's Society of Catholic Chinese Physicians of Shanghai"; Correspondence; Brochures; "Ce qu'on dit de l'École française de médecine a Changhai"
  - Missionary Schools - Aurora University (Box 12, Folder 299)
    "Ce qu'on dit de l'École française de médecine a Changhai"; Translations
  - Missionary Schools - Translations (Box 12, Folder 300)
  - Missionary Schools - China vs. West Cartoon (Box 12, Folder 301)
  - Missionary Schools - Arthur H. Smith - Boxer Indemnity (Box 12, Folder 302)
    "Theodore Roosevelt and Arthur Smith"
  - Missionary Schools - Tsing Hua College, Boxer Indemnity (Box 12, Folder 303)
    Excerpt from "Handbook of Cultural Institutions in China"; Correspondence and Notes
  - Missionary Schools - "Thomas Cochrane, Pioneer and Missionary Statesman" by F. French (Box 12, Folder 304)
  - Missionary Schools - "Anatomy in China" by E.V. Cowdry (Box 12, Folder 305)
  - Missionary Schools - "George Rogers Hall: 'Pills and Plants'" by George E. Gifford, Jr. (Box 12, Folder 306)
  - Missionary Schools - "Hangchow Medical Training College" by S.D. Sturton (Box 12, Folder 307)
  - Missionary Schools - Pennsylvania Medical College (Box 12, Folder 308)
    "Pennsylvania Medical College: Being the Medical Department of St. John's University, Shanghai" by J.C. McCracken
  - Missionary Schools - China Medical Association Medical Education Requirements, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 309)
  - Missionary Schools - "Medical Education in China" (Box 12, Folder 310)
  - Missionary Schools - Paulun Fischer (Box 12, Folder 311)
    "Two Chinese Universities: Before and After the Cultural Revolution" by P.J. Alley; "Die Deutsche Medizinschule für Chinesen in Schanghai"; Notes and Translations
  - Missionary Schools - Plague in California (Box 12, Folder 312)
    "Plague in San Francisco in 1900: The United States Marine Hospital Service Commission to Study the Existence of Plague in San Francisco" by Loren George Lipson
  - Missionary Schools - Gen. Tada re: SMR (Box 12, Folder 313)
    "'The Basic Conception of China' as Viewed by the Japanese Army" by Major-General Hayao Tada
  - Missionary Schools - Goodrich Book Review (Box 12, Folder 314)
  - Missionary Schools - Hankow-Mukden (Box 12, Folder 315)
    "The Future of Hankow Union Hospital and the Re-Building of Central China's Medical Missionary Enterprise" by Keith H. Gillison
  - Missionary Schools - Hope Hospital (Box 12, Folder 316)
    "The Story of Hope Hospital" by Samuel Cochran
  - Missionary Schools - "William Lockhart: Pioneer of Medical Missions and First Guy's Missionary" by Simon S. Brook (Box 12, Folder 317)
  - Missionary Schools - London Missionary Society (Box 12, Folder 318)
  - Missionary Schools - Medical Missionary (Box 13, Folder 319)
    "A Conflict of Professions: The Medical Missionary in China" by Theron Kue-Hing Young
  - Missionary Schools - The Moukden Medical College (Box 13, Folder 320)
    "The Moukden Medical College" by S.A. Ellerbek
  - Missionary Schools - Dermatology and Syphilology (Box 13, Folder 321)
    Report of the Division of Dermatology and Syphilology of the National Medical College of Shanghai (1929-1937)" by F. Reiss
  - Missionary Schools - Training Chinese, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 322)
  - Missionary Schools - Chengtu, West China (Box 13, Folder 323)
    "China Mission Accomplished" by Wilder Penfield; "The Medical School of Union University, Chengtu, West China" by W.R. Morse; "Some Aspects of Medical Education in the 'Orient'" by Leslie G. Kilborn
  - Missionary Schools - Shantung Christian University (Box 13, Folder 324)
    Notes; Correspondence; "The Origin and Development of the School of Medicine of Shantung Christian University" by R.T. Shields
  - Missionary Schools - Yale-in-China (Box 13, Folder 325)
  - Missionary Schools - "Joint Conference of the China Medical Missionary Association and the National Medical Association of China, Address by Dr. Wu Lien-Teh" (Box 13, Folder 326)
  - Peking Union Medical College - PUMC Alumni Today (Box 13, Folder 327)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Unfoldered Materials (Box 13, Folder 328)
    Book Jacket, "Western Medicine in a Chinese Palace: Peking Union Medical College, 1917-1951" by John Z. Bowers; Correspondence with Atsumi Minami
  - Peking Union Medical College - ABMAC Bulletin (Box 13, Folder 329)
    Correspondence; Notes; "The ABMAC Bulletin, 1969-1972" (with gaps)
  - Peking Union Medical College - PUMC Alumni Association, Yu Wang Fu Association Address List (Box 13, Folder 330)
  - Peking Union Medical College - American Philosophical Society Material on PUMC (Box 13, Folder 331)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Marshall Balfour, Miscellaneous Documents (Box 13, Folder 332)
    Correspondence; "Memorandum on Rockefeller Foundation Activities in China (1935-44) for the Inter-Divisional Committee" by M.C. Balfour
  - Peking Union Medical College - Claude Barlow (Box 13, Folder 383)
    Notes; "Experimental Ingestion of the Ova of 'Fasciolopsis buski'; Also the Ingestion of Adult 'Fasciolopsis buski' for the Purpose of Artificial Infestation" by Claude H. Barlow; "Voluntary Infection with 'Schistosoma haematobium'" by Claude Heman Barlow and Henry Edmund Meleney
  - Peking Union Medical College - Davidson Black, Peking Man, from Meet Your Ancestors, R.C. Andrews (Box 13, Folder 334)
  - Peking Union Medical College - W.B. Cannon (Box 13, Folder 335)
    "Walter Bradford Cannon, George Higginson Professor of Physiology" by Joseph Garland
  - Peking Union Medical College - Stephen Chang (Box 13, Folder 336)
    "Foot Prints on the Sands of Time"; "Report by Dr. Stephen Chang on PUMC" to Claude E. Forkner (closure of PUMC)
  - Peking Union Medical College - George Char, Letter from Jean Curran (Box 13, Folder 337)
  - Peking Union Medical College - The Capital Hospital (Box 13, Folder 338)
    "What's in a Name" from Rockefeller Foundation Staff and Program News
  - Peking Union Medical College - Rockefeller Foundation Report of China Medical Commission and Burton (Box 13, Folder 339)
    Envelope, Burton Commission; Envelope, Second China Medical Commission; Envelope, First China Medical Commission; Notes
  - Peking Union Medical College - Bacon F. Chow Biographical Resume (Box 13, Folder 340)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Chronology (Box 13, Folder 341)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Samuel R. Detwiler Biographical Material (Box 13, Folder 342)
  - Peking Union Medical College - A.M. Dunlap (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Evil PUMC (Box 13, Folder 344)
    "Why Did American Imperialism Establish the Peking Union Medical College" by the Research Committee of the Chinese Union Medical College; "Acupuncture - The Scientific Evidence" by Han Suyin; "U.S. Imperialist Cultural Aggression Disguised as Friendship" by the Revolutionary Committee of the China Medical College; Notes; "Thoroughly Criticize and Repudiate the Eight-Year Medical Education Program Pushed by China's Kruschov" by the Revolutionary Committee of the China Medical College, Peking; "The Revolutionaries of a Medical College Denounce the Revisionist Line in Education"
  - Peking Union Medical College - R.B. Fosdick (Box 13, Folder 345)
    "A Memoir of Raymond Blaine Fosdick - 1883-1972" by J. George Harrar
  - Peking Union Medical College - C.N. Frazier, Dermatology, Harvard Medical School (Box 13, Folder 346)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Gates to Greene, Mission - CMB (1916) (Box 13, Folder 347)
  - Peking Union Medical College - A.B. Hastings (Box 13, Folder 348)
    "A Biochemist's Anabasis" by A. Baird Hastings
  - Peking Union Medical College - Victor Heiser re: Papers (Box 13, Folder 349)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Henry Street Settlement (Box 13, Folder 350)
    Brochures; Newsletters
  - Peking Union Medical College - R. Hoeppli (Box 14, Folder 351)
    "The Hoeppli Phenomenon in Schistosomiasis. Comparative Pathology and Immunopathology" by Franz von Lichtenberg, Jerome H. Smith, and Allen W. Cheever
  - Peking Union Medical College - Paul Hodges, Development of Western Medicine in China (Box 14, Folder 352)
    "History of Medicine in China" by Paul C. Hodges; "The Development of Western Medicine in China" by Paul Hodges; Untitled Manuscript by Paul D. Hodges; Correspondence; "A Radiological Odyssey" by Paul C. Hodges
  - Peking Union Medical College - Notes from Interview with Gertrude E. Hodgman, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 353)
  - Peking Union Medical College - H.S. Houghton Biographical Material (Box 14, Folder 354)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Harvey J. Howard, Trachoma Research (Box 14, Folder 355)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Harvey J. Howard, "My Bandit Clinic" (Box 14, Folder 356)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Obituary of Hu Shih (Box 14, Folder 357)
    Notes; "Hu Shih (1891-1962)"; "Hu Shih and the May 4th Movement" by Yu Chiu-yu
  - Peking Union Medical College - Interview with C. Keefer, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 358)
  - Peking Union Medical College - King-Yu-Loo Interviews (Box 14, Folder 359)
    "Serve the People Better" by Lin Chiao-chih; Envelope, Yu, T'sai Fan; Envelope, Chih-Teh Loo, Dick Loo; Envelope, Gordon King-Interview, J.P. Maxwell
  - Peking Union Medical College - Robert Koh-Seng Lim (Box 14, Folder 360)
    Notes; "Robert Kho-Seng Lim: Doctor, Soldier, Patriot" by George E. Armsrong; Biographical Material
  - Peking Union Medical College - Morgan Liu (Box 14, Folder 361)
    Envelope, M. Liu Interview
  - Peking Union Medical College - Harold Loucks (Box 14, Folder 362)
    Correspondence, Loucks to Bowers, Kaung to Bowers
  - Peking Union Medical College - Richard S. Lyman (Box 14, Folder 363)
    Correspondence; "Report on Impressions of Neuropsychiatry in China"
  - Peking Union Medical Colelge - John R. McKelvey Interview, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 364)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Franklin C. McLean, Various Reprints (Box 14, Folder 365)
    Obituary; Bibliography; "The McLean Campaigns for Full-Time Academic Medicine" by Marshall R. Urist; "Chemical Warfare" by Franklin C. McLean; "The Happy Accident" by Franklin C. McLean; Book Review, "'A History of the Rockefeller Institute, 1901-1953' by George W. Corner" by Franklin C. McLean
  - Peking Union Medical College - I. McQuarrie (Box 14, Folder 366)
    Cartoon, "Medical Rounds on Ward G-3, PUMC"; Correspondence
  - Peking Union Medical College - Frank L. Meleney, Biographical Material (Box 14, Folder 367)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Henry E. Meleney, Obituaries (Box 14, Folder 368)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Eugene L. Opie (Box 14, Folder 369)
    Obituaries; "Tuberculosis of First Infection and of Reinfection; Their Frequency in Chinese People of Peking" by Eugene L. Opie; "Tuberculosis of First Infection in Adults from Rural Districts of China" by Eugene L. Opie; Referee's Report, "Traditional Chinese Medicne" by Opie; Correspondence and Notes
  - Peking Union Medical College - Nurses - Interviews (Box 14, Folder 370)
    Gertrude E. Hodgman; Gertrude Ai-Ching Pao; Mrs. Tseng; Anne McCabe; Daisy Wu; Miss Zia; Mrs. Szutu; Mrs. Wang; Jane Long; Notes
  - Peking Union Medical College - Francis W. Peabody (Box 14, Folder 371)
    "The Care of the Patient" by Francis Weld Peabody; Notes; "The Department of Medicine at Peking Union Medical College" by Francis W. Peabody
  - Peking Union Medical College - PUMC Today (Box 14, Folder 372)
    Correspondence; "Oriental Renaissance in Education and Medicine" by Wilder Penfield; "The Chinese People's Republic: A Physician's Observations" by Wilder Penfield
  - Peking Union Medical College - Bernard Emms Read Biography (Box 14, Folder 373)
    Photograph; Notes
  - Peking Union Medical College - Carl Schmidt (Box 14, Folder 374)
    "Half a Century of Ephedrine" by K.K. Chen; "New Challenges for Clinical Pharmacology" by Carl F. Schmidt; "Ephedrine after 40 Years" by Carl F. Schmidt; "Some Experiences with Chinese Drugs" by Carl F. Schmidt
  - Peking Union Medical College - Aura E. Severinghaus Biographical Material (Box 14, Folder 375)
  - Peking Union Medical College - W.W. Stifler (Box 14, Folder 376)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Adrian Taylor (Box 14, Folder 377)
    Copies of Correspondence from Halstead Collection, Johns Hopkins
  - Peking Union Medical College - Harry B. van Dyke (Box 15, Folder 378)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Donald D. Van Slyke (Box 15, Folder 379)
    Obituaries/Biographical Memoirs
  - Peking Union Medical College - "Patterns and Effectiveness of Past and Present Overseas Programs of Cooperation in Medical Education and a Forecast of the Future" by Robert Briggs Watson (Box 15, Folder 380)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Chester Montague Van Allen (Box 15, Folder 381)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Jerome P. Webster (Box 15, Folder 382)
    "The Story of Plastic Surgery at the Columbia-Presbyterian Medical Center"
  - Peking Union Medical College - World War II, Letter from D. Kaung (Box 15, Folder 383)
  - Peking Union Medical College - Hsien Wu Biography (Box 15, Folder 384)
  - Peking Union Medical College - James Yen, Various Reprints (Box 15, Folder 385)
    Interview; "An Overview, 1970" by the International Institute of Rural Reconstruction; "Scientific Medicine as Applied in Ting Hsien" by C.C. Ch'en; "For the World's Forgotten: A Long-Proven, Down-to-Earth Program" by Clarence W. Hall; "Jimmy Yen: China's Teacher Extraordinary" by J.P. McEvoy; "Self-Help: Jimmy Yen's Proven Aid for Developing Nations" by Carter Davidson; "Rural Reconstruction: An Idea Whose Time Has Come" by the International Institute of Rural Reconstruction;' "The Ting Hsien Experiment" by Y.C. James Yen; "Tell The People: Talks with James Yen about the Mass Education Movement" by Pearl S. Buck
  - Peking Union Medical College - Faculty, Picture from J. Snyder (Box 15, Folder 386)
    Photocopy of picture; "Fatal Infection of Irradiated White Mice with European Typhus by the Intra-Abdominal Route" by P.Y. Liu, John C. Snyder, and John F. Enders; "The Susceptibility of the Rodents 'Gerbillus gerbillus' and 'Gerbillus pyramidum', to Experimental Typhus Infection" by J.C. Snyder, C.J.D. Zarafonetis, and Wei T'ung Liu
  - Peking Union Medical College - Van Slyke, Wu, and McLean (Box 15, Folder 387)
    "Studies of Gas and Electrolyte Equilibria in the Blood, V. Factors Controlling the Electrolyte and Water Distribution in the Blood" by Donald D. Van Slyke, Hsien Wu, and Franklin C. McLean
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - "A Review of Ancient Chinese Anatomy" by E.T. Hsieh (Box 15, Folder 388)
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - "On Chinese Medicine" by P.K. Liang (Box 15, Folder 389)
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - "China's Greatest Naturalist; A Brief Biography of Li Shih-Chen" by Gwei-Djen Lu (Box 15, Folder 390)
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - "Records of Diseases in Ancient China" by Lu Gwei-Djen and Joseph Needham (Box 15, Folder 391)
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - "Medieval Preparations of Urinary Steroid Hormones" by Lu Gwei-Djen and Joseph Needham (Box 15, Folder 392)
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - Miyasita - Chemistry - Japan, China (Box 15, Folder 393)
    "A Link in the Westward Transmission of Chinese Anatomy in the Later Middle Ages" by Saburō Miyasita; "Sôkichi Hashimoto (1763-1836), Pioneer Pharmacologist" by Saburô Miyasita; "Pancreas Known by the Chinese in the Middle Ages!" by Saburô Miyasita; "Western Alchemy Symbols in a Japanese Medical Work" by Theodor Benfey
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - "Proto-Endocrinology in Medieval China" by Needham and Lu (Box 15, Folder 394)
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - "Alchemy in China" by William Jerome Wilson (Box 15, Folder 395)
  - Chinese Traditional Medicine - Chinese Traditional Medicine (Box 15, Folder 396)
    "Man as Medicine: Pharmacological and Ritual Aspects of Traditional Therapy Using Drugs Derived from the Human Body" by William C. Cooper and Nathan Sivin; "Appendix I: On Understanding the Language of Early Chinese Chemistry and Pathology: A Bibiographical Essay" by N. Sivin; "Folk Medicine and Classical Medicine in Traditional China" by N. Sivin; Grant Application, "Projects in Traditional Chinese Medicine" by Nathan Sivin
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - Manchu Anatomy (Box 15, Folder 397)
    "French Jesuits and the 'Manchu Anatomy' - How China Missed the Vesalian Revolution" by T. Kue-Hing Young
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - Koxinga (Box 15, Folder 398)
    "Koxinga and a Chinese Restoration" by Donald J. Senese; "The Fall of Siena" by Judith Hook
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - "The New China: Some Medical Impressions" by T.F. Fox (Box 15, Folder 399)
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - London Missionary Society (Box 15, Folder 400)
    "Church Missionary Society: Facts about China" tract (1903)
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - Macartney Embassy to China, 1793-1794, Dr. Gillan's Observations (Box 15, Folder 401)
    "Kowtowing in China" by Jonathan Spence; "Dr. Gillan's Observations on the State of Medicine, Surgery, and Chemistry in China"
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - "Progress of Pediatric Work in China in the Past Eight Years" by Chu Fu T'ang (Box 15, Folder 402)
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - Adam Schall (Box 15, Folder 403)
    "Opening of the Adam Schall Residence of United College" from The University Bulletin, The Chinese University of Hong Kong
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - "7 Green Pea Street: The Canton Ophthalmic Hospital and Its Founder" by Charles Snyder (Box 16, Folder 404)
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - US-Salem and China Trade (Box 16, Folder 405)
    "Cargoes of Splendor" by Vera D. Hahn and Mary Evans
  - Introduction of Western Medicine - "Wang Jen-Tsün: A Late Nineteenth Century Obstructer of the Introduction of Western Science" by George H.C. Wong (Box 16, Folder 406)
  - General - Miscellaneous Correspondence re: China (Box 16, Folder 407)
  - General - "Major University Reopens in Peking" (Box 16, Folder 408)
  - General - Nakayama, Joseph Needham (Box 16, Folder 409)
    "Joseph Needham - Organic Philosopher" by Shigeru Nakayama; "Chinese Medicine" by Joseph Needham and Lu Gwei-Djen; "The Optick Artists of Chiangsu" by Joseph Needham and Lu Gwei-Djen; "Skin-colour in Chinese Thought: An Extract from a Letter to the Editor" by Joseph Needham
  - General - "Russian-Chinese Clashes in Border Area Began in 17th Century" by Theodor Shabad (Box 16, Folder 410)
  - General - "The Nanyang Chinese Anti-Japanese and Boycott Movement, 1908-1928" by Yoji Akashi (Box 16, Folder 411)
  - Chinese Medicine Today - Old Ways Linger (Box 16, Folder 412)
    "The Old Ways Linger: CHinese Herb Doctors Still Treat Taiwanese"; "Chinese Patent Medicine"
  - Chinese Medicine Today - "Progress of Surgery in China" by Wu Ying-K'ai (Box 16, Folder 413)
  - Chinese Medicine Today - Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 414)
  - Chinese Medicine Today - "Synthesis of the Occidental and Oriental Medicines in the Teaching Curriculum at Hue Medical School" by Bui Duy Tam (Box 16, Folder 415)
  - Chinese Medicine Today - "Senior Medical Personnel and Popular Physicians Go to the Countryside" (Box 16, Folder 416)
  - Chinese Medicine Today - Acupuncture (Box 16, Folder 417)
    "Acupuncture Anaesthesia: An Anaesthetic Method by Combination of Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine" by Shanghai Acupuncture Anaesthesia Co-ordinating Group; Acupuncture Charts; "Peking Review, no. 25, Mao Tsetung Thought Lights Up the Way for the Advance of China's Medical Science" by Hou Chin-wen; "Acupuncture Anesthesisa in the People's Republic of China" by John J. Bonica; "Therapeutic Acupuncture in the People's Republic of China: Implications for American Medicine" by John J. Bonica
  - Chinese Medicine Today - "Deaths Show Many in Modern Hong Kong Cling to Old Traditions and Beliefs" (Box 16, Folder 418)
  - Bibliography - Chinese Medicine (Box 16, Folder 419)
  - Bibliography - Annotated Bibliography on Public Health in China, Tsung-Yi Lin, Lillian Ling-wen Lin (Box 16, Folder 420)
  - Unfoldered Materials - Photocopies, ten Rhyne (Box 16, Folder 421-422)
    Related Materials
    Related to files in Series 1, Western Medicine in Japan
  - Unfoldered Materials - Notebook, Notes and Interviews (Box 17, Folder 423)
- The Health of Mankind, 5.5 Cubic Feet
  This series contains research and reference materials related to Bowers' book The Health of Mankind, a history of the Rockefeller Foundation's work in medicine and the natural sciences. Files include reprints, articles, notes, translations, and several drafts of the book chapters.
  - Unlabeled Folder (Box 17, Folder 424)